<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>Cyanobot's Genes</name>
    <author>cyanobot</author>
    <packageId>cyanobot.CyanobotsGenes</packageId>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.4</li>
		<li>1.5</li>
    </supportedVersions>

    <description>7 new xenotypes and 47 new genes (16 cosmetic, 31 functional) to add to your gene pool. Requires Biotech.
        
Genes:
- 3 templates that generate genes dynamically from loaded xenotypes
--- Offspring: carriers have offspring of a different xenotype to themselves
--- Metamorphosis: carriers transform into a different xenotype at adulthood
--- Implanter: carriers can implant a specific xenotype into others (not necessarily their own)
- 2 hemogen-powered abilities
- Bodyfeeder gene for getting hemogen primarily from human flesh
- 5 diet genes: herbivores, carnivores, and obligate cannibals
- more/less/no Recreation need
- mental break threshold raised/lowered
- 3 body size genes
- 3 aging genes
- Precocious gene that allows infants to take care of themselves from birth
- genetic blindness/mutism
- 7 trait-forcing genes including 2 new traits
- claws, fangs, and tough skin
- 14 more miscellaneous
- head frills, tusks, and nostril slits
- tabby-patterned fur
- 2 tails
- 2 blood colors, 3 eye colors, 1 alternative eye graphic
- 3 hair bundles containing 17 hair colors
- 3 skin bundles containing 17 skin colors

Xenotypes:
- Biodrone : Emotionally dampened supersoldiers. Not quite as potent as Hussars, but far more controllable. Stoic and resilient, but inept at most non combat tasks.
- Changeling : Beautiful, flighty children found mysteriously without parents. They eat a lot, sleep a lot, and don’t work hard, but everyone loves them.
- Fairy : The ironically named adult form of the changeling. Hulking, highly aggressive brutes with toxic spittle and great strength and speed.
- Glimmer (requires Outland - Genetics) : Hopelessly lost glitterworlders unsuited for life on the Rim. Intelligent, cheerful, intensely sociable, clumsy, herbivorous, and extremely distressed by violence.
- Kitlin : Useless cat people who spend all their time sleeping or playing. They are quick and agile and have a knack for shooting.
- Psycrux (requires VRE - Archon) : Intensely powerful psycasters and psychic parasites, able to implant others with a Thrall xenogerm to more readily enslave them and feed on their psyches.
- Thrall (requires VRE - Archon) : Created by Psycrux, thralls are easily controlled. They work most hours of the day, needing no recreation and little sleep, but they are slow in everything they do.
- Shulk : Highly specialised pioneers for settling remote cave systems. Self-sufficient with natural weapons for hunting, tough skin, strong immune systems and the ability to eat pretty much anything, but mute and extremely light sensitive.
- Wist : Hemogen-powered battlefield medics who use bloodfeeding to power coagulation and a potent, addictive, venomous bite that dulls pain, fights infection, and elevates mood.
    </description>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
			<displayName>Harmony</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>
		<li>
			<packageId>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</packageId>
			<displayName>Biotech</displayName>
			<downloadUrl>https://store.steampowered.com/app/1826140/RimWorld__Biotech/</downloadUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
	<modDependenciesByVersion>
		<v1.4>
			<li>
				<packageId>telardo.BetterGeneGraphicsFramework</packageId>
				<displayName>Better Gene Graphics Framework</displayName>
				<downloadUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2880940958</downloadUrl>
			</li>
		</v1.4>
		<v1.5>
			<li>
				<packageId>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</packageId>
				<displayName>Vanilla Expanded Framework</displayName>
				<steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2023507013</steamWorkshopUrl>
				<downloadUrl>https://github.com/Vanilla-Expanded/VanillaExpandedFramework</downloadUrl>
			</li>
		</v1.5>
	</modDependenciesByVersion>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>brrainz.harmony</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
		<li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
		<li>telardo.BetterGeneGraphicsFramework</li>
		<li>EBSG.Food</li>
		<li>EBSG.AiO</li>
	</loadAfter>	

</ModMetaData>